

## **Amelia Claire Reiser**

750 Barber St. Athens, GA 30601 (405)306-0080

Age: 22 Height: 5'7" Weight: 135 Hair Color: Red

Eye Color: Dark Brown

A classically trained dancer with 18 years of dance training and over 10 years of pre-professional performance experience; an emphasis on classical ballet training, formal contemporary training, and other dance experience ranging from tap, jazz, character, hip-hop, ballroom, and aerial dance. A strong technical background with experience in improvisation and composition allows for adaptability, quick retention of choreography, and a respect and dedication to all aspects of the performing arts world.

## Performance Experience

Diavolo Dance Theater, Company B / September 2010

Performed in AWOL.

UGA CORE Concert Dance Company / 2009-2010

Contemporary and Aerial Dance Concert Company

**Perpetual Motion Modern Dance, Oklahoma Contemporary Dance Festival / Summer 2009**Contemporary and Trapeze

Senior Exit Dance Concert / 2007-2010

Performed senior student choreography, and choreographed with the University of Georgia **Young Choreographers Series /** 2007-2009

Performed and choreographed with the University of Georgia

#### **Dance Education**

University of Georgia Dance Department, Athens GA	2007 – Present	
Ballet I - IV, Contemporary I - IV, Pointe, Pas de Deux, Jazz I - III, Improvisation, Composition,		
Pilates		
University of Oklahoma School of Dance, Norman OKSpring 3	2007, Spring 2009	
Modern technique I-II, Ballroom Dancing I		
Classical Ballet Academy, Norman OK	1991-2007	
Ballet, Pointe, Jazz, Tap, Hip-Hop, Modern		

### **Festivals**

Shen Wei Arts Workshop with Javier Bācá, San Diego Dance Theater, CA	Vinter 2010
Bates Dance Festival, Lewiston, MESu	mmer 2010
American Dance Festival Winter Intensive, NYC.	Winter 2009

## **Academic Honors and Awards**

University of Georgia Dean's List	Spring and Summer 2008, Spring 2010
National Honor Society	2003-2007
National Student Leadership Conference	Summer 2006
Education	
University of Georgia	2007 - Present
Graduating Class: Spring 2011	
<b>GPA</b> : 3.35	
University of Oklahoma	2006-2007, Spring 2009
<b>GPA</b> : 3.42	
Norman High	

# Work Experience

**GPA**: 3.78

Information Desk UGA Tate Student Center, Athens, GA / June 2010 - Present

Dance instructor Classical Ballet Academy, Norman, OK / 2005-2006, Summer 2009

Student Gallery Assistant, Jacobson House Native American Art Gallery, Norman, OK / Spring and Summer 2009

## Other activities

Dance/USA Member, / 2010 - Present Delta Gamma Sorority / 2007 - Present

**Volunteer**, Full Plate, food program for homeless shelters, Athens, GA / 2008 **Volunteer**, Center for Children and Families, family emergency foster care / 2001-2007